<class name = "zproto_example" signature = "0" title = "zproto example protocol">
This is an example protocol designed to teach you how this stuff works.

The class name tells the code generator what .c and .h to generate. Use
the same name as you're using for this .xml file.

The signature is put into every protocol message and lets us filter bogus
or unknown protocols. It is a 4-bit number from 0 to 15. Use a unique value
for each protocol you write, at least.

<include filename = "license.xml" />

You can define constants. These are put into the header file, prefixed by
the class name, so e.g. #define ZPROTO_EXAMPLE_VERSION  1

<define name = "VERSION" value = "1" />

You can optionally define a header that will be repeated at the start of
every message. This is just a kind of macro.

<header>
    <field name = "sequence" type = "number" size = "2" />
</header>

The protocol consists of one or more 'messages', each consisting of one or
more 'fields'. You number the messages with unique 'id's. We could do this
automatically but experience tells us it's better to do this by hand, so
you can provide forward compatibility by defining new message ids yourself
and leaving old ones as-is.

A field has a type and possibly a size. zcodec insists that a field with a
given name have the same type and size anywhere you use it in a protocol.
This keeps your APIs and grammars sane.

There are a few ways to version a protocol. You could use a version number
in the header. You could add it to the first message in a conversation, as
FILEMQ does.

The best way to avoid lots of breaking changes in a protocol is to split
the fields into those that rarely change, and those that often change, and
to put the second lot into hash tables (the 'dictionary' type).

OK, let's see some meat.

<message name = "LOG" id = "1">
    <field name = "level" type = "number" size = "1">Log severity level</field>
    <field name = "event" type = "number" size = "1">Type of event</field>
    <field name = "node" type = "number" size = "2">Sending node</field>
    <field name = "peer" type = "number" size = "2">Refers to this peer</field>
    <field name = "time" type = "number" size = "8">Log date/time</field>
    <field name = "data" type = "string" size = "2">Actual log message</field>
Log an event.
</message>

Note that you can add a short comment for each field, and for the message.
Use these, it helps when reading the source code.

zproto supports numbers (unsigned integers) of 1, 2, 4, and 8 bytes. If you
don't specify the size, it's 1 byte by default.

zproto supports strings encoded as length + data, in the proper ZeroMQ style,
without trailing nulls or any of that language-specific stuff. The length
can, again, be 1, 2, 4, or 8 bytes, and defaults to 1 byte.

Strings contain UTF-8 data; that is, no zero bytes. Their encoded size is the
number of bytes in the string (not including the size field).

zproto supports lists and hashes of strings:

<message name = "STRUCTURES" id = "2">
    <field name = "aliases" type = "strings">List of strings</field>
    <field name = "headers" type = "dictionary">Other random properties</field>
This message contains a list and a hash.
</message>

You should read the zproto_example.h file quite carefully to see what API
these field types generate.

zproto supports three kinds of binary data. First, you can define a raw octet
string with fixed size. You can use this to encode short binary strings. Do
not use for anything longer than e.g. 256 octets, as octet strings are not
variable length.

Second, you can define frames, which are sent as separate ZeroMQ frames on
the wire. This is ideal for variable-size binary data such as images, or
other blobs.

Lastly, you can define ZeroMQ messages (that is, one or more frames). This
is useful for protocols that want to wrap entire ZeroMQ messages in other
data. If you use a "msg" type field, it must be the last field in the
message.

<message name = "BINARY" id = "3">
    <field name = "flags" type = "octets" size = "4">A set of flags</field>
    <field name = "address" type = "frame">Return address as frame</field>
    <field name = "content" type = "msg">Message to be delivered</field>
Deliver a multi-part message.
</message>

</class>
